Next, let's make the skirt.
The skirt is to support the outer skirt structure,
to make the structure more three-dimensional.
Use the rectangle tool,
click and drag in the 2D window,
draw a rectangle that is twice as wide as the belt.
Its length is the length of the skirt we will make later.
Then we press Shift F to open the arrangement,
arrange these two skirt panels on the side of the thigh,
and then to the attribute editor,
make the frame wider,
so that the panel and the body do not have a gap.
Then switch to the line pattern tool,
click the panel outline,
create the skirt and waist,
and the skirt itself,
its front and back pattern lines.
Open the control key to simulate.
After the simulation,
we will see that the skirt panel is already worn on the body.
In the 3D draft menu,
we can find the line pattern,
and the frame display.
When we turn on the frame display,
we can see the grid distribution on the panel.
It can be seen that when the particle diameter is 20,
the grid is relatively small.
If we reduce the particle diameter to 10,
because the grid is more,
its overall simulation is more detailed,
and it will make the panel look softer.
We can also reduce the impact thickness,
and reduce the air thickness between the panel and other panels.
Then we can return to the thick texture surface.
Only in the thick texture surface,
under the clothing display style,
we can see the thickness of the panel.
If you don't think there are enough folds here,
we can widen the skirt panel,
but after widening,
because our grid is increased according to the original trend,
so there may be a difference in the back.
So we can right-click on the panel,
select Rearrange 3D Arrangement Position,
to rearrange the panel,
return it to the time when it was just arranged,
and then start to simulate again.
After the simulation,
if there are some differences,
we can give this skirt a level.
Because other panels have levels of 0,
so we apply a level of 1 to the skirt,
and it will naturally pass to the outside.
After the simulation is stable,
we return the level to 0.
Here we will see that there is a difference in the belt,
because we modified the skirt panel that we sewed together with it.
So here we apply a level of 1 to the belt,
and re-simulate it.
After re-activating the simulation,
we will see that the skirt white
is a little bit deformed.
So when we select the belt,
we click on the fabric window to apply the new fabric.
For the new one,
we only use the fabric on the belt,
we need to improve its gold tail,
sand strength,
and the tension of the corner line.
These three values are the stretch performance
of the gold tail and the corner line of the panel.
The higher these three values,
the more difficult it is for the fabric to stretch,
so even if the skirt panel is very large,
it will not affect the belt panel,
and it will not be deformed.
If you want the fabric to stretch more easily,
you can set it in reverse.
Next, let's learn
what effects the bending strength will have.
Here we select the skirt panel,
click on the Shift key,
you can choose more,
apply them to a new piece of fabric.
When the bending strength is higher,
the whole fabric will become harder.
In this case,
the number of folds will decrease,
and the single fold will become larger and wider,
and it will look thicker.
And the panel itself has a certain support.
When the bending strength of the panel is lowered,
it looks softer,
not so hard,
and its overall elasticity looks better.
Then we press Ctrl C
to return to the bending strength of the modification.
We first activate the inner layer of the clothing,
let it be simulated with other panels,
and we return the excess layers to 0.
Because the frozen panel,
it will maintain its own shape,
and after the deflation,
we need to simulate it first,
to prevent some conflicts and instability
caused by too many panels being deflated at the same time.
After the simulation is stable,
we can freeze the top again.
For the skirt of the lower body,
if you think its length is too short,
we can directly drag the selection frame of the selected panel
and lengthen its skirt.
Note that we are stretching down,
stretching down.
Of course, you can use the adjustment panel tool
or the edit panel tool
to drag the bottom down.
When you are stretching,
don't stretch it too much at a time,
otherwise the grid will extend along the original shape,
and it may have some conflicts and instability.
If you want to shorten it,
it is the same,
pull the bottom up here.
Remember to simulate every time you modify the panel,
and let them modify it.
As a group,
because we can't see the wrinkles inside it,
so you can also reduce the number of wrinkles
according to the need.
To reduce the number of wrinkles,
it is very simple,
just shrink the panel.
As we did the tie part before,
because later we will add another layer of skirt
on the outside of the skirt,
so we first use a relatively low
end-to-end shrink rate for these two panels
to shrink it up.
If there are still some wrinkles,
we will reduce the end-to-end shrink rate a little more,
so that it looks like there are no wrinkles on the surface,
and make the structure of the outer layer.
Then we can freeze all the panels.